VISHRUTA PATIL

♥ MUMBAI, India ☑ vishrutapatil2106@gmail.com in linkedin.com/in/vishruta-patil-30106b204

Projects: github.com/Vishruta-Patil M Blogs: vishrutapatil2106.medium.com

▶ Portfolio: https://vishrutapatil.netlify.app

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Hardworking computer engineering student (9.25 GPA) with experience in programming outside the University courses. Aiming to apply knowledge and implement programming skills to successfully fit the suitable role at your company. Frequently praised as focused by my peers, I can be relied upon to help your company to achieve its goals.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering - B.E, Computer Engineering, University Of Mumbai

July 2019 – present

Aggregate - 9.25 C.G.P.A, Graduating in 2023

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

FullStack Web Developer, Techq konnect

June 2021 - present

- Working and building the web apps using MERN stack, Django.
- Responsible for integrating multiple machine learning models and payment gateway integrations in the web app.
- Also working on building database and developing the frontend and backend of the web applications.

Open Source Contributor, *GirlScript Summer of Code* March 2021 – May 2021

- Contributed to the web-app project by adding and modifying features of the newsletter, chatbot, authentication of web app using React for frontend and Nodejs, Express for the backend. The database used was MongoDB.
- Also worked in the C/C++, java-based projects on implementing various algorithms and data structures to solve complex problems.

SKILLS

• Languages: C/C++, Java, JavaScript

• Front-End: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React

Back-End: Nodejs, Express, Django, Flask

• Libraries: React-Router, MongooseJS

• Database: MongoDB, MySQL, SQL server

• Developer Tools: Git, VS Code, Azure Web Apps

BLOGS

Authentication in Web Development ☑ Sorting Algorithms ☑

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Microsoft Learn Student Ambassador ♂

July 2021 - present

As a Microsoft learn student Ambassador, I get to learn new skills using Microsoft resources, connect and collaborate with professionals and create an impact in the student Tech communities.

PROJECTS

VChat App ♂

- VChat App is a Realtime Chat Application. It allows users to have a group chat and there is a feature of a chat room where users can chat about different topics in the specific room.
- It displays the group name and the names of participants of the group chat. Users are updated if someone has joined or left the group. The welcome message is displayed to the new user and there are also timestamps on the messages.
- Technologies Ûsed: HTML, CSŠ, JavaScript, Nodejs, Express, Socket.IO, Momentjs

Netflix Clone ☑

- Netflix clone with react using TMDb and movie trailer API. Implemented using Firebase hosting.
- The landing page has collections of movies for recommendations of different genres. Every movie is linked with the movie trailer.
- Technologies Used: HTML, CSS, React, Firebase

Gracious Givers 🛮

- Gracious Givers reduce the gap between the people who are willing to help and the people who are searching for such volunteers
- The donation website to accept donation amounts, sending confirmation receipt to the donor through email instantly, notifying the amount of donation to the organization, and updating people regarding the services provided by the organization.
- Technologies Used HTML, SCSS, EJS, JavaScript, Nodejs, Express

AWARDS

Scholarship holder in Secondary Scholarship Examination, Maharashtra State Council of Examination

Scholarship holder in Primary Scholarship Examination, Maharashtra State Council of Examination

Secured in top 30 teams, IEEE APSIT Hackathon

Secured in top 50 teams, Kharagpur Data Analytics Group presents Summer AI Challenge

Maths Concept Examination, Grade A

CERTIFICATES

Microsoft AI Classroom Series

Data Science life cycles and cognitive services, Building machine learning models on Azure

APSCRIPT Hackathon Certificate

Conducted by IEEE APSIT. Selected in top 30 teams in web development domain

Mastering Data Structures and Algorithm in C and C++

Implementation of Data Structure and Algorithms in real world problems and find the best fit solution.